<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advanced Simulation Library</title>
    <description>Open source hardware accelerated multiphysics simulation software</description>
    <link>http://asl.org.il/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://asl.org.il/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 13:54:13 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 13:54:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avtech Scientific announces cooperation with IBM and NVIDIA.</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;video class=&quot;post&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; poster=&quot;/media/posts/ASL_benchmark_K80_poster.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;source src=&quot;/media/posts/ASL_benchmark_K80.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		Your browser does not support the video tag.
	&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Multicomponent flow benchmark on NVIDIA Tesla K80 GPU. &lt;a href=&quot;/media/posts/ASL_benchmark_K80.mp4&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the SC15 conference Avtech Scientific announces its cooperation with IBM and NVIDIA (both are platinum members of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://openpowerfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;OpenPOWER Foundation&lt;/a&gt;) in the area of high-performance scientific computing. Initial efforts will focus on comparative testing and benchmarking of the open source Advanced Simulation Library on vendors’ hardware with subsequent performance tuning. The long-term objective is to ensure ASL’s optimal productivity on the OpenPOWER platform, smooth user experience and the availability of detailed documentation of the ASL deployment procedure on all related accelerators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/-gWWpkd3YWE&quot;&gt;benchmark video&lt;/a&gt; of the ASL’s standard &lt;a href=&quot;/benchmarks/multicomponent_flow/&quot;&gt;multicomponent flow test&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates impressive results, obtained on a single NVIDIA Tesla K80 GPU with Intel Xeon E5-2690 10-core 3GHz serving as host. They will be used as a basis for evaluation of POWER8 performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;numerical-setup-and-performance&quot;&gt;Numerical setup and performance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;number of grid points: over 10’500’000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;number of unknowns: over 63’000’000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;physical time: 25 s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;number of iterations: 10’000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;computation time: &lt;strong&gt;390 s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/11/12/Avtech_Scientific_announces_cooperation_with_IBM_and_NVIDIA/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/11/12/Avtech_Scientific_announces_cooperation_with_IBM_and_NVIDIA/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ASL assists neurosurgeons and robots, computes brain deformation in real time.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/posts/brain_with_falx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brain deformation simulation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open source &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;ASL&lt;/a&gt; was successfully utilized in the cognitive and diagnostics module of the medical robot developed within the framework of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.active-fp7.eu/index.php/resultsmenu/intraopbs.html&quot;&gt;ACTIVE project&lt;/a&gt; (WARNING: graphic images). Simulation of the brain shift process during a craniotomy procedure was implemented to facilitate robot-assisted awake neurosurgery. Despite the fact that it incorporates many physical effects into the underlying mathematical model, operates on a large simulation domain with high resolution - it is 100 times faster than the real time even if deployed on a regular laptop. This remarkable performance allowed to determine unknown patient and operation specific model parameters intra-operatively “on the fly” through iterative smart guessing and subsequent calibration of the intermediate results with the stereo camera observations. This way a full picture of brain deformation was generated, which is otherwise not available to the surgeon through direct examination by means of ultra sound, video cameras or MRI. This synthesized information, as common in image guided surgery, is used by the robot and/or physician for navigation, operative planning and identifying the target location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Covered on:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technology.org/2015/09/14/asl-assists-neurosurgeons-and-robots-computes-brain-deformation-in-real-time/&quot;&gt;Technology.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://interestingengineering.com/how-asl-assists-neurosurgeons-and-robots/&quot;&gt;InterestingEngineering.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/08/30/ASL_assists_neurosurgeons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/08/30/ASL_assists_neurosurgeons/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ASL enters Linux distributions at a record-breaking pace.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Less than 24 hours after the much-requested &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/09/ASL-0.1.2_released/&quot;&gt;update of dependencies&lt;/a&gt; to the current state of the art, and under a month from its initial public release, ASL entered Arch Linux. All major distributions (and by extension their derivatives/clones) have followed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/packages/libasl/&quot;&gt;libasl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debian: &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/testing/libasl-dev&quot;&gt;libasl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fedora: &lt;a href=&quot;https://admin.fedoraproject.org/pkgdb/package/libASL/&quot;&gt;libASL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gentoo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cgit.gentoo.org/proj/sci.git/tree/sci-libs/asl&quot;&gt;asl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OpenSuse: &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.opensuse.org/download.html?project=science&amp;amp;package=ASL&quot;&gt;ASL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu: &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.ubuntu.com/wily/libasl-dev&quot;&gt;libasl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/07/31/ASL_enters_Linux/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/07/31/ASL_enters_Linux/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ASL 0.1.2 released - updating dependencies.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the numerous requests from the community ASL dependencies were updated in the latest version 0.1.2 as follows: VTK 6.1, Boost 1.55, MATIO 1.5.2.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/06/09/ASL-0.1.2_released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/06/09/ASL-0.1.2_released/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avtech Scientific releases the source code of ASL to the community.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://avtechscientific.com&quot;&gt;Avtech Scientific&lt;/a&gt; announces the first open source &lt;a href=&quot;/download&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; of its Advanced Simulation Library. The software will be distributed under the free GNU Affero General Public License (AGPLv3) with an optional &lt;a href=&quot;/licensing&quot;&gt;commercial license&lt;/a&gt;. The company hopes that this step will encourage collaboration with the user community accelerating the extension of ASL and lead to sustaining of its high quality standards. Following the release Avtech Scientific is looking for partners among embedded systems vendors (FPGA, DSP) and GPU/APU manufacturers to bring its innovative technology to new hardware platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced Simulation Library is a free and open source hardware accelerated multiphysics simulation software. Its computational engine is based, among others, on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lattice_Boltzmann_methods&quot;&gt;Lattice Boltzmann Methods&lt;/a&gt; and is written in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenCL&quot;&gt;OpenCL&lt;/a&gt; which enable &lt;a href=&quot;/benchmarks&quot;&gt;extraordinarily efficient deployment&lt;/a&gt; on a variety of massively parallel architectures, ranging from inexpensive FPGAs, DSPs and GPUs up to heterogeneous clusters and supercomputers. The engine is hidden entirely behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://asl.org.il/doc/Developer-Guide/locomotive_8cc-example.html&quot;&gt;simple C++ classes&lt;/a&gt;, so that no OpenCL knowledge is required from application programmers. ASL can be utilized to model various coupled physical and chemical phenomena and employed in a multitude of fields: computational fluid dynamics, virtual sensing&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, industrial process data validation and reconciliation, image-guided surgery, computer-aided engineering, design space exploration, crystallography, etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khronos.org/news/archives/avtech-scientific-open-sources-its-opencl-based-advanced-simulation-library&quot;&gt;Announcement on Khronos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khronos.org/opencl/resources/opencl-libraries-and-frameworks-with-opencl-acceleration&quot;&gt;ASL among Khronos OpenCL resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Virtual or soft sensors are applications for simulation-based monitoring and control of industrial processes, used to provide feasible and economical alternatives to hardware sensors if the latter are unavailable, impractical or do not provide sufficient information. Virtual sensors are often deployed on embedded systems but can also run on more powerful hardware depending on the complexity of the underlying model and operational needs. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/05/14/open-sourcing_ASL/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/05/14/open-sourcing_ASL/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
