<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advanced Simulation Library</title>
    <description>OpenCL-enabled open source multiphysics simulation software package</description>
    <link>http://asl.org.il/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://asl.org.il/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 11:04:58 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 11:04:58 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avtech Scientific releases the source code of ASL to the community.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://avtechscientific.com&quot;&gt;Avtech Scientific&lt;/a&gt; announces the first open source &lt;a href=&quot;/download&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; of its Advanced Simulation Library. The software will be distributed under the free GNU Affero General Public License (AGPL) with an optional &lt;a href=&quot;/licensing&quot;&gt;commercial license&lt;/a&gt;. The company hopes that this step will encourage collaboration with the user community accelerating the extension of ASL and lead to sustaining of its high quality standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced Simulation Library is a free and open source multiphysics simulation software package. Its computational engine is based, among others, on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lattice_Boltzmann_methods&quot;&gt;Lattice Boltzmann methods&lt;/a&gt; and is written in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenCL&quot;&gt;OpenCL&lt;/a&gt; which enable &lt;a href=&quot;/benchmarks&quot;&gt;extraordinarily efficient deployment&lt;/a&gt; on a variety of massively parallel architectures, ranging from inexpensive FPGAs, DSPs and GPUs up to heterogeneous clusters and supercomputers. The engine is hidden entirely behind C++ classes, so that no OpenCL knowledge is required from the application programmers. ASL can be utilized to model various coupled physical and chemical phenomena, especially in the field of CFD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://asl.org.il/2015/05/14/open-sourcing_ASL/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://asl.org.il/2015/05/14/open-sourcing_ASL/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
